# ALI YAZDI

Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran ma.yazdi75@gmail.com • ma.yazdi75@aut.ac.ir • +98 (912) 037-1375 • aliyazdi.tech

#### ABOUT ME

I have been working as a Flutter developer and mobile team leader for two years. I am a CS graduate who interests in using Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering in my work experiences. I am an open-source advocate who helps developers to solve their problems in development. I am looking for a better opportunity and willing to relocate to a new country.

### WORK **EXPERIENCE**

Mate Machine Inc., North Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada - Remote

Jun 2020 - Present

• Working as a flutter developer team leader to launch the application in three months.

Tarafdari, Tehran, Iran

Mar 2019 – May 2020

Flutter, Drupal, Laravel, MySQL

- Working as a mobile application team leader at one of the most popular sport social media.
  - R&D about Flutter framework and migrating the android application to Flutter application includes multimedia content, live score matches, and sports TV streaming with live chat on the socket.
  - We could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to the flutter.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Amirkabir University of Technology, (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran

- Bachelor of Engineering (BSc.) in Computer Engineering, Software, Ranked 2nd in Iran. Sep 2015 – Jan 2020
  - Thesis: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
  - Adviser: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati

#### Adab High School. Tehran, Iran

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

Sep 2011 - Jun 2014

#### **HONORS & AWARDS**

■ First Place in the 12th Iran Web and Mobile Festival (IWMF)

• For the Best Sport Mobile Application among 7k applications

Feb 2020

Most installed sport application in Iran

May 2020

- In my first job, we could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to the flutter
- Ranked in top 0.2% among more than 180K participants

- Jul 2015
- Qualified for the Second Round of Olympiad among more than 70K participants
- In Nation-Wide University Entrance Exam among all Iranian Student of Physics and Mathematics
  - In the Iranian Physics Olympiad and Mathematical Olympiad

Jul 2013

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **MEDIUM**

- [1] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 1)", Using Software Engineering methods to design and build a fully responsive and adaptive mobile, desktop, and web application, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.
- [2] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 2)", Designing and building the Flutter application structure using the Bloc pattern in the micro-service architecture, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.
- [3] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 3)", Designing and building the Flutter application data models and backend using the Build value and Bloc pattern, Flutter Community, Jan 2021.

### **PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS**

■ The Flutter Protfolio Application, Flutter

▲ 🐧 🌐

- Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform.
- The Flutter Gallery Application, Flutter



- Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform using micro-service architecture.
- The Flutter Media Notification Plugin, Java, Flutter
  - · Designing and Building a Flutter Plugin that helps developers to show their media notification and control streaming media beyond their Flutter application.
- The Location-Based Recommendation System, Django, Django Rest Framework, Scikit-learn, Flutter
  - Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System with Djando and Flutter.

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning
- Software Engineering

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Artificial Intelligent and Robotics Lab, Amirkabir University of Technology,

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

- Undergraduate Research Student, Science Department
  - Project: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
  - · Supervisors: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati
  - Focus: Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Data Analytics

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Persian: Native language
- English: Fluent, working proficiency

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### Programming Languages

Dart, Python, Java, C/C++, PHP, Assembly

#### **■** Mobile Development

Flutter, Android

#### Database Systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL

#### Operating System

Linux (Ubuntu)

#### Web Development

Django, Django Rest Framework

#### Other

Microcontroller Programming, Bash Scripting

# ACADEMIC PROJECTS

#### Programming Languages, racket

• NUMEX-Interpreter: Designing a simple interpreter NUMEX programming language with Racket.

#### ■ Information Security, python

 My-Security-Course: Encryption with MD5, SHA256, DES, working with cryptool software nmap and using ms08\_067 exploitand.

### ■ Computer Networks, python

 DNS-UDP-TCP-Proxy: A python proxy that receives HTTP packets on UDP then sends them on TCP with DNS server.

#### ■ Microprocessor & Assembly Language, C

• Digital-Watch-with-LCD: A digital watch with LCD and alarm using microcontroller ATMEGA16.

#### ■ Data Structure & Algorithms, Java

• Finite-State-Machine: Creating four types of data structure and searching using AVL-tree, balance-TST, trie-tree and hash.

#### Advanced Computer Programmings, Java

• Planet-vs-Zombies: A 2d game similar to Plant vs Zombies game using java object oriented programming.

#### REFERENCES

#### Professor Mohammad Rahmati

Professor of Department of Computer Engineering, Amirkabir University of Technology, Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran rahmati@aut.ac.ir • +98 (21) 645-42741

### HOBBIES

- Watching TV Shows & Movies, (Christopher Nolan's Fan)
- Listening & Playing Musics, (Playing 3Tar: A Persian Instrument)
- Playing Volleyball & Video Games, (Dota2 Player-Steam: Ranked Ancient)
- Watching Twitch & Talking with other people in Discord

[*Last Update on 2021-01-14*] • [Clone me on [7]]